Thomas J. Mallinson fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Thomas J. Mallinson fonds
1950 - 1990
F-124
Q104443798
25 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Mallinson, Thomas J.
Thomas J. (Tom) Mallinson (191--1999) was a professor of Communication Studies at Simon Fraser University. Trained as a clinical psychologist, Mallinson came to the newly-founded SFU in 1965 to head the Centre for Commuications and the Arts within the Faculty of Education. The Centre later evolved into the School for Communication.
published
Full
Revised
Title is based on provenance of the fonds.
The fonds consists of records made and received by Tom Mallinson in his role as a professor and as a consultant for outside organizations. Includes correspondence, lectures and publications.
The fonds was arranged by the Archivist.
Communications
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
Please consult the inventory for the School of Communication.
Series descriptions and file lists are available. A more detailed biographical sketch is available in the hard copy version of the finding aid maintained in the Archives Reading Room.
- Correspondence, 1959 - 1990; F-124-1; 13 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of correspondence relating to Tom Mallinson's professional interests as a psychologist at the University of Toronto and his academic career as a professor of Communications Studies at SFU. Also includes a file containing correspondence and drafts for a proposed book of reminiscences about the early history of the SFU.
  - Correspondence, 1959 - 1968; F-124-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 124-1)
    Textual records
    Open
  - Correspondence, 1969 - 1971; F-124-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 124-1)
  - Correspondence, 1972 - 1975; F-124-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 124-1)
  - Correspondence, 1976 - 1977; F-124-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 124-1)
  - Correspondence, 1979 - 1990; F-124-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 124-1)
  - Correspondence - SFU History Book, 1986 - 1990; F-124-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 124-1)
- Research files, 1950 - 1980; F-124-2; 13 cm of textual records
  Series consists of lectures, publications, correspondence and other records relating to Tom Mallinson's research projects and outside consultations. Includes samples of Mallinson's curriculum vitae.
  - Research interests, CV, 1961 - 1973; F-124-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Lecture - Development, Character, 1950 - 1959; F-124-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Lecture - Good Parent, 1950 - 1959; F-124-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Lecture - Psychological Factors in Marriage, 1950 - 1959; F-124-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Lecture - Self Understanding, 1950 - 1959; F-124-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Lecture - Semantics of Personal Adjustment, 1950 - 1959; F-124-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Lecture - Training in Creative Thinking, 1950 - 1959; F-124-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Lecture - A Psychologist Looks at Language, 1956; F-124-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Lecture - Self-directed Personality, 1962; F-124-2-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Gifted Underachievers, 1960 - 1980; F-124-2-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Publications - General 1/3, 1962 - 1967; F-124-2-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Publications - General 2/3, 1962 - 1967; F-124-2-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Publications - General 3/3, 1962 - 1967; F-124-2-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Articles on Theory, 1962 - 1964; F-124-2-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Canadian Commission on Human Relations Training, 1962 - 1968; F-124-2-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 124-2)
  - Communication Workshop, 1973; F-124-2-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 124-2)